A Guide to the Audrey Windsor Bergner Research Collection, ca. 1900 - 2007
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Audrey Windsor Bergner Research Collection ca. 1900 - 2007
Thomas Balch Library
VC 0014
This collection consists of research materials largely relating to the old plantation and historic homes in Middleburg, VA, and which served as research material for Audrey Windsor Bergner when she wrote her books, Old Plantations and Historic Homes around Middleburg, Virginia, vols. 1-3.
Audrey Windsor Bergner
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Audrey Windsor Bergner, Middleburg, VA
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
2006.0164, 2006.0172, 2010.0211
Historical Information
Audrey Windsor Bergner was born in 1929 and attended St. John's University, where she graduated with a major in History. She taught genealogy in California before moving to Middleburg, Virginia in 1993. She wrote "The Visitor's Guide to Middleburg" and then produced Old Plantations and Historic Homes around Middleburg, Virginia: And the Families Who Lived and Loved within Their Walls, vols. 1-3. These volumes seek to capture the society and culture that existed in "Hunt Country," focusing on the wealthy families and noble houses of Middleburg, Virginia. Bergner passed away in 2010.
Middleburg, Virginia was established in 1787 by Leven Powell. Positioned halfway between Alexandria and Winchester, Middleburg served as a rest stop for those who traveled Ashby Gap Road, now U.S. Highway 50, which connected the Potomac River with the Shenandoah Valley for trading. Middleburg served as a meeting place for both Union and Confederate troops during the Civil War. After the Civil War, Middleburg fast became known as the "Nation's Horse and Hunt Capital," due to its ideal landscape beneath the Blue Ridge Mountains and the elegant homes in which the elite hunters could reside.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of photographs, captions for select photographs, newspaper articles, letters, diary entries, historic documents, real estate advertisements, event invitations, biographical "sketches," copies of legal documents, historical reports, timelines, event programs, wine labels, and photograph negatives largely relating to the old plantation and historic homes in Middleburg, VA, and which served as research material for Audrey Windsor Bergner when she wrote her books, Old Plantations and Historic Homes around Middleburg, Virginia, vols. 1-3. Photographs comprise the majority of the collection. Inclusive dates of the collection are 1900-2007, with the majority of photographs taken in the 1990s and 2000s. Most older documents are photocopies of originals. In many cases, properties are identified by name only; property addresses are not available.
Folders are organized alphabetically by name of house with which the material corresponds; most photographs are in VC 0014 Boxes 1 and 2, with oversized photographs and documents arranged in a parallel manner in the manuscript boxes.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Bergner, Audrey Windsor. Old Plantations and Historic Homes around Middleburg, Virginia and the Families Who Lived and Loved within Their Walls. Vol. 1. New York: Cornwall Books, 2001.
"History Of The Rte 50 Corridor." Route 50 Corridor Coalition. Accessed 24 Aug 2009. www.route50.org/history.html.
"Middleburg Online - History." Middleburg, Virginia, Loudoun County. Accessed 06 Aug 2009. www.middleburgonline.com/history.asp.
Other Finding Aid
Past Perfect Catalogue Records
Technical Requirements
None
Related Material
Audrey Windsor Bergner, Old Plantations and Historic Homes Around Middleburg, Virginia: And the Families Who Lived and Loved Within Their Walls, 3 Volumes, V REF 975.528 BER; Lewis/Edwards Architectural Surveys of Loudoun County 1972-2007 (M 022); Additional Loudoun County Architectural Surveys 2003 (M 011); African American Architectural Surveys 2004 (M 013).
Contents List
- Airmont (4 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:1)
- Aspen Hill (27 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:2)
- Ayrshire (15 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:3)
- Berkley House (10 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:4)
- Bittersweet (19 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:5)
- Bolling Brook (22 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:6)
- Briar Patch (24 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:7)
- Butcher's Run (8 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:8)
- Carr House (18 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:9)
- Carter House (12 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:10)
- Chestnut Hill (18 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:11)
- Church & Camp Meeting Revival, 1920s (4 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:12)
- Crednal (56 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:13)
- Creek Hill (18 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:14)
- Denton (10 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:15)
- Dover House (10 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:16)
- Dresden (14 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:17)
- Exning, Carriage House (17 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:18)
- Exning, Creamery (5 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:19)
- Exning, Dairy Barn (9 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:20)
- Exning, Log Cabin (17 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:21)
- Exning, Manor House (32 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:22)
- Fair View (9 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:23)
- Farmer's Delight (22 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:24)
- Featherbed Farm (4 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:25)
- Foxcroft (17 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:26)
- Glen Ora (22 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:27)
- Gravestones -- Dulany -- Carter (6 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:28)
- Groveton (26 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:29)
- Groveton -- Fairview (10 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:30)
- Groveton Outbuildings (8 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:31)
- Hatcher House (2 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:32)
- Hatcher House -- Old (3 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:33)
- Huntland (12 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:34)
- Leith (0 photographs, see M 048 Box 1)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:35)
- Little Oatlands (8 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:36)
- Llangollen (23 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:37)
- Mercer House (23 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:38)
- Miller's House (34 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:39)
- Mosby Spring Farm (13 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:40)
- Mount Beulah (26 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:41)
- Mount Defiance (19 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:42)
- Mount Gilead (28 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:43)
- Mount Gilead -- Bodine House (2 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:44)
- Mount Gilead -- Eaton House (5 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:45)
- Mount Harmony (12 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:46)
- Myrtle Hall Farm (9 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:47)
- Noland Ferry House (41 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:48)
- Oakham (13 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:49)
- Old Loudoun County Courthouse (2 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:50)
- Old Welbourne (33 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:51)
- Patterson House -- Drawings on Attic Wall (16 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:52)
- Poor House Farm (21 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:53)
- Pot House (13 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:54)
- Powell Family Reunion and Sally Mill House (8 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:55)
- Raspberry Plains (12 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:56)
- Rokeby (23 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:57)
- Rose Hill (42 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:58)
- Round Hill RR Station (2 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:59)
- Selma (8 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:60)
- Seven Springs (8 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:61)
- Shelburne (25 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:62)
- Sleepy Hollow (13 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:63)
- Stoke (38 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:64)
- Sunny Bank Farm (13 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:65)
- Toll House (4 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:66)
- Trappe Spring (20 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:67)
- Valley View, Swedenburg Vinyard (13 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:68)
- Vine Hill (24 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:69)
- Waverly Piedmont Vineyard (17 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:70)
- Welbourne Plantation (35 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:71)
- Welbourne Plantation -- Old Church House (8 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:72)
- Misc. photos relating to the books (20 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:73)
- Misc. photos unrelated to the collection (8 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:74)
- Ayrshire (18 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:75)
- Atoka Store (12 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:76)
- Black Middleburg (2 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 1:77)
- Buchanan Hall (5 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:78)
- Belvoir (21 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:79)
- Forts and Ferries (21 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:80)
- Gordonsdale (37 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:81)
- Hitching Post (4 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:82)
- John Janney House (14 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:83)
- Return to Mosby See (2 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:84)
- Loudoun Court House (5 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:85)
- Mill at Leeton Forest (25 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:86)
- Myrtle Hall (9 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:87)
- Paris, Virginia (30 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:88)
- Rectortown (45 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:89)
- Champe (2 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:90)
- Photos from Linda Dodderidge (7 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:91)
- Mayors of Middleburg (6 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:92)
- Wolf Crag, Ashby (14 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:93)
- Old Schools (12 photographs)n.d. (Box:folder VC 0014 Box 2:94)
- Airmontn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:1)
- Aspen Hilln.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:2)
- Ayrshiren.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:3)
- Berkley Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:4)
- Bittersweetn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:5)
- Bolling Brookn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:6)
- Briar Patchn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:7)
- Butcher's Runn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:8)
- Carr Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:9)
- Carter Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:10)
- Chestnut Hilln.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:11)
- Church & Camp Meeting Revival 1920s (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:12)
- Crednaln.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:13)
- Creek Hilln.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:14)
- Dentonn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:15)
- Dover Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:16)
- Dresdenn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:17)
- Exning, Carriage Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:18)
- Exning, Creameryn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:19)
- Exning, Dairy Barnn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:20)
- Exning, Log Cabinn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:21)
- Exning, Manor Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:22)
- Fair Viewn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:23)
- Farmer's Delightn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:24)
- Featherbed Farmn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:25)
- Foxcroftn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:26)
- Glen Oran.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:27)
- Gravestones -- Dulany -- Cartern.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:28)
- Grovetonn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:29)
- Groveton -- Fairviewn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:30)
- Groveton Outbuildingsn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:31)
- Hatcher Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:32)
- Hatcher House -- Oldn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:33)
- Huntlandn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:34)
- Leithn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:35)
- Little Oatlandsn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:36)
- Llangollenn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:37)
- Mercer Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:38)
- Miller's Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:39)
- Mosby Spring Farmn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:40)
- Mount Beulahn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:41)
- Mount Defiancen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:42)
- Mount Harmonyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:43)
- Mount Gileadn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:44)
- Mount Gilead -- Bodine Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:45)
- Mount Gilead -- Eaton Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:46)
- Myrtle Hall Farmn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:47)
- Noland Ferry Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:48)
- Oakhamn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:49)
- Old Loudoun County Courthousen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:50)
- Old Welbournen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:51)
- Patterson House -- Drawings on Attic Walln.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:52)
- Poor House Farmn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:53)
- Pot Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:54)
- Powelln.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:55)
- Raspberry Plainsn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:56)
- Rokebyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:57)
- Rose Hilln.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:58)
- Round Hill RR Stationn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:59)
- Selman.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:60)
- Seven Springsn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:61)
- Shelburnen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:62)
- Sleepy Hollown.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:63)
- Stoken.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:64)
- Sunny Bank Farmn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:65)
- Toll Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:66)
- Trappe Springn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:67)
- Valley View, Swedenburg Vinyardn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:68)
- Vine Hilln.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:69)
- Waverly Piedmont Vineyardn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:70)
- Welbourne Plantationn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:71)
- Welbourne Plantation -- Old Church Housen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:72)
- Misc. photos relating to the books n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:73)
- Misc. photos unrelated to the collectionn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:74)
- Ayrshire -- notes and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:75)
- Atoka Store -- notesn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:76)
- Black Middleburg -- notes and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:77)
- Buchanan Hall -- notes and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:78)
- Bodine House -- notes, genealogy, and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 1:79)
- Belvoir-- notes, genealogy, and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:1)
- Christmas -- newspaper articlesn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:2)
- Dara Parker -- correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:3)
- Forts and Ferries -- notes n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:4)
- Gordonsdale -- notesn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:5)
- Hitching Post, Book 3. Old Tavern -- notesn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:6)
- John Janney House -- notes n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:7)
- Return to Mosby See -- picturesn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:8)
- Leesburg Court House -- notes and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:9)
- Mill at Leeton Forest -- notes and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:10)
- Paris -- notes and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:11)
- Stony Lonesome -- notes and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:12)
- Rectortown -- notes, genealogy, and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:13)
- Raspberry Plains -- notes n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:14)
- Old Schoolsn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:15)
- Wolf Crag, Ashby -- notes and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:16)
- Lettersn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:17)
- Howell Press -- notes and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:18)
- Ashburn -- newspaper articlen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:19)
- Adams Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:20)
- Allen Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:21)
- Heritage Book -- newspaper articlen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:22)
- Ashby Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:23)
- Aldie -- map n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:24)
- Ayre Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:25)
- Myrtle Hall -- negatives n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:26)
- Photos from Linda Dodderidgen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 2:27)
- Bolyn Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:1)
- Bodine Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:2)
- Barker, Bark, Barlow, Binns Families -- genealogy n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:3)
- Buchanan Family-- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:4)
- Brooks, Belmont, Broun, Beveridge Families -- genealogy n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:5)
- Benton, Beall, Young, Curriers Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:6)
- Breckinridge Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:7)
- Cox Family -- genealogy n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:8)
- Cemetaries -- Rogers, Carter, Chinn, McCarty, Powell, Craunn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:9)
- Civil War -- songs, Mountain Rangers, Loudoun soldiers, Mosby, Confederate soldiers -- Rector n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:10)
- Chilton and Chinn Familes -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:11)
- Carter Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:12)
- Currencyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:13)
- Cary, Carr, Cochran, Colston Families -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:14)
- Champe, Craun, Campbell, Carroll, Needham -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:15)
- Dulany Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:16)
- DeLashmutt, Denham, Dudley, Douglass -- genealogy n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:17)
- DeButts, DiZerega, Delaplane, Dodd -- genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:18)
- Dixie Song and Widow's Dowern.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:19)
- Edward's Ferry, Exning, Jamestown, Foxhunting Songsn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:20)
- Fairfax Family -- notes n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:21)
- Francis House and Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:22)
- Fletcher, Fred, Frazier, Furr -- genealogy n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:23)
- Foxcroft, Farmer's Delight, Fauquier Countyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:24)
- Gibson, Gibbs, Glascock, Glassgow, Green, Gulick, Gunnell -- genealogy n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:25)
- Hall, Haxell, Hite, Hopkins, Hulbert, Hutchison -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:26)
- Harrison, Hatcher, Hixson -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:27)
- Humphrey -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:28)
- Huguenot, Hibbs Bridge, Heron's Court, Hickory Tree Farmn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:29)
- Ish, Ilsley Murder, Janney, Jazz Music, Keyes, Kinchelot, Kinlochn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:30)
- Kinsley Mill, Insights Magazine -- (pg 9)Feb/March 2002 (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:31)
- Lake, Lemon, Lickey, Litchfield, Littlejohn, Love, Lacey, Lanen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:32)
- Lewis, Littleton, Lucketts, Leith -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:33)
- Lee Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:34)
- Long Branch Baptist Church, Ayrshire, Aldie, Lake Schoolhouse, Llangollen, Leesburgn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:35)
- Martz, Matthews, McCabe, McCormick, McIlhaney, McVeigh, Miley, Morison, Mountn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:36)
- McCarty -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:37)
- Monroe and Mercer -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:38)
- Mosby and Mosby Rangers -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:39)
- Mason Family Chartn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:40)
- Newspaper Articles -- Black Middleburg, Churches, Ulysses Grant, Loudoun Western Townsn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 3:41)
- Macsville, Manassas, Manor of Leeds, Marshall Bank, Middleburg, Mountville, Mill House, Miller House, Myrtle Halln.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:1)
- Neville -- Death n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:2)
- Noland -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:3)
- Oak Hill and Oatlandsn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:4)
- Palmer, Pelham, Poston, Potts -- genealogy, notes, and property recordn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:5)
- Peyton Family -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:6)
- Powell -- genealogy, notes and correspondencen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:7)
- Powell Family Recordsn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:8)
- Randolph, Rector, Rixley, Rock Hill Farms, Russell, Rust, Rutledge Farmn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:9)
- Rogers, Roszell -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:10)
- Revolutionn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:11)
- Scott, Seaton, Shreve, Skinner, Slater -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:12)
- Smith, Smiths, Stuart, Swart -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:13)
- Strother -- notes, correspondence and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:14)
- Shelbourne, Slavery, "Sundown Towns" -- notes n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:15)
- Tabb, Threlkeld, Triplett, Turner, Tylern.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:16)
- U.S. in 1904, Virginia Heritagen.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:17)
- Tucker, Ward, West, White -- notes and genealogyn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:18)
- Whiting, Williams, Wiltshire, Wirt, Withersn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:19)
- War of 1812 -- Wikipedia article and CDn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:20)
- Old Welbourne, Weston, Wind Fields -- notes n.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:21)
- Mapsn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:22)
- Misc. Articlesn.d. (Box:folder M 048 Box 4:23)